aapd.org 2018-12-24

# Privacy Policy | The American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry

The American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry (AAPD) respects the privacy of our members and other users of our website.[](file:///C:/Users/tmchenry/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/CP3D1XYD/Privacy%20Policy-FINAL%20April%202013.docx#_ftn1) This Privacy Policy addresses our use of information about you collected by virtue of your use of the website. The latest version of our Privacy Policy will always be available on the website. We welcome your comments or questions about our Privacy Policy and privacy practices. If you feel that this site is not following its stated policy, please let us know. You may contact us about this Privacy Policy:

By mail:            American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry

211 E. Chicago Ave., Suite 1600  
Chicago, IL 60611   

By e-mail:         [slitch@aapd.org](mailto:slitch@aapd.org)

Although we are committed to insuring your privacy, we may be required to disclose personal information when required by law and necessary to comply with a court order or legal process.The AAPD has also implemented privacy policies that are consistent with the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation.

**_Information We May Collect About You_**

The information AAPD collects via our website is used to improve the content and advance the AAPD’s mission. We collect: domain name and internet protocol (IP) address of visitors to our website; aggregate information on what pages users access or visit; user-specific information on what pages users access or visit; and information volunteered by users, including from surveys, purchases and/or registrations. We also may collect the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail.

The AAPD uses cookies for a number of purposes, including administering the website and recording session information, such as items that users add to their shopping cart and user-specific information on what pages were accessed or visited.

To gain access to members-only resources and personalization features on the website, members are asked to provide a unique user ID and password. AAPD’s web server tracks the domain names and IP addresses (not the individual e-mail addresses) of members entering the members-only area, but only for purposes of measuring the general number of visits, pages visited, average time spent on the site, etc. 

**_How We May Use Information We Collect_**

The AAPD and its affiliates may use your contact information to alert you to new information, products and services, events, and other opportunities. From time to time, we may also make your contact information available to other reputable organizations whose products or services we think you might find interesting.

###### The AAPD uses information voluntarily submitted by AAPD members and others to provide members with personalized service tailored to your needs and to enable us to continually improve the convenience and functionality of this site. For example, we maintain a directory of pediatric dentists that may include information that an AAPD member submitted via our website. 

The AAPD has instituted stringent reviews and opt-out capabilities to ensure that you do not receive unwanted e-mail from the AAPD. 

The AAPD uses industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving consumer data exchanged with our site. We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site. When users choose to make payments via credit cards, we submit the information needed to obtain payment to the appropriate clearinghouses. We do not store or reuse this credit card information.

**_Your Rights_**

To help us protect your privacy, please contact us as indicated above if you believe your information is being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected.

If you do not want to receive e-mail, postal mail, telephone calls or faxes from us in the future, or if you do not want us to share your contact information in the manner described above, please provide us with your exact name, e-mail and postal addresses, phone and fax numbers and, if appropriate, AAPD membership number. We will no longer use information you so identify and will do our best to be sure any other specific contact information is removed from any list we share with other organizations.

On request we provide site visitors with access to all information that we may maintain about them, including financial information, unique identifier information, transaction information, communications that the visitor has directed to our site, and contact information. On request we also offer visitors the ability to have inaccuracies corrected in contact information, financial information, unique identifiers, transaction information, and communications that the visitor has directed to the site.

**_Children’s Privacy_**

If you are under 18 years of age, you may not purchase products or services from, and you should not provide information to, the AAPD website without the involvement of a parent or guardian. We do not collect online contact information without prior parental consent or parental notification, including an opportunity for the parent to prevent use of the information and participation in the activity. Without prior parental consent, online information will be used only to respond directly to the child's request and will not be used for other purposes. We do not entice, by the prospect of a special game, prize or other activity, the disclosure of more information than is needed to participate in the activity.
